Finding Aid for the Katherine Anne Porter Letters to Margaret Winkler, 1946-1967 LSC.1517
UCLA Library Special Collections
Katherine Anne Porter Letters to Margaret Winkler
1946-1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Porter, Katherine Anne
LSC.1517
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Katherine Anne Porter (1890-1980) worked for the Fort Worth critic (1917) and the Rocky Mountain news (1918), lectured, and accepted various appointments as writer-in-residence at several universities (1945- ). Her published books include: Flowering Judas and other stories (1935), Pale horse, pale rider (1939), and Ship of fools (1962). The collection consists of correspondence and cards from Katherine Anne Porter to Margaret Winkler, some printed materials, and photographs.
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE. Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Joan Palevsky, 1987.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9927228713606533
Biography
Born as Callie Russell Porter on May 15, 1890 in Indian Creek, Texas; worked for the Fort Worth critic in 1917 and the following year joined the staff of the Rocky Mountain news; spent extended periods of residence in Mexico, 1920-31; went to Europe in 1931; after 1945, she lectured and accepted various appointments as writer-in-residence at several universities; her published books include: Flowering Judas and other stories (1935), Pale horse, pale rider (1939), and Ship of fools (1962); she wrote to Margaret Winkler, who worked in the Westwood Book Store in Westwood, California; died September 18, 1980 in Silver Spring, Maryland.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence and cards from Katherine Anne Porter to Margaret Winkler. Also contains some printed materials and photographs of Porter, her home, and her friends.
Related Material
Katherine Anne Porter Papers. Available at Archives & Manuscripts Department, University of Maryland, College Park.
Letters.; Women novelists, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Porter, Katherine Anne -- Correspondence; Winkler, Margaret, addressee.
- n.d., 5 items.
  - Autograph card signed. Hotel West Weston, New York., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Autograph letter signed. 26 October. Olympic Hotel, San Francisco., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Typewritten letter signed. 18 or 19 August. Stearns Hotel, Ludington, Michigan., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Typewritten letter signed., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Typewritten letter signed. "16 June" pencilled at top of page., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1946, 2 items.
  - Autograph card., March 12, 1946; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autograph letter signed. With envelope., December 25, 1946; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1947, 2 items.
  - Typewritten letter signed. With envelope., December 7, 1947; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Autograph letter signed. With envelope., December 1947; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1948, 6 items.
  - Typewritten letter signed., June 21, 1948; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Typewritten letter signed., June 2, 1948; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Typewritten letter signed., September 20, 1948; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Typewritten letter signed., October 12, 1948; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Typewritten letter signed., November 11, 1948; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Autograph card signed., November 27, 1948; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1949, 13 items.
  - Typewritten letter signed., January 1, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., February 21, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., March 2, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autograph card signed. Postmark date only., March 9, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autograph card signed., April 12, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., April 25, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autograph card signed., May 15, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., May 19, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., May 23, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autograph card signed., June 1, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., June 21, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., September 15, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten letter signed., December 23, 1949; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1950, 3 items.
  - Typewritten letter signed., February 21, 1950; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Typewritten letter signed., March 21, 1950; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Autograph card signed., August 20, 1950; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1953, 1 item.
  - Typewritten letter signed. With envelope., May 16, 1953; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1954, 1 item.
  - Typewritten letter signed., June 17, 1954; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1955, 4 items.
  - Autograph card signed. Written on 12th Night, 1956., February 5, 1955; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Autograph card signed., February 1, 1955; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Typewritten letter signed., May 24, 1955; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Autograph card signed., June 17, 1955; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1957, 2 items.
  - Typewritten letter signed., May 26, 1957; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Typewritten letter signed., October 5, 1957; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1959, 1 item.
  - Typewritten letter signed., January 14, 1959; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1962, 2 items.
  - Autograph card signed. Hotel Eden, Rome., June 9, 1962; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Autograph card signed. Hotel Prince de Galles, Paris., December 4, 1962; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1966, 1 item.
  - Typewritten letter signed. Washington, D.C., April 22, 1966; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1967, 1 item.
  - Autograph card signed., May 14, 1959; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 9 items.
  - Photograph. "Lucifer in the glass-room", June 21, 1957; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. "Last Christmas 1956 with cards on manelpiece.", December 1956; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. Porter Home, [Roxbury Road, Southbury, Connecticut]., n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. Photograph in postcard format of Katherine Anne Porter., 1954; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. "Paul made this in the bay window of the House in Roxbury Road. K.A.P.", April 1956; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. "Front from Northeast near driveway. Paul made this." With envelope., January 2, 1956; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. [Katherine Anne Porter on stairway with dog]., n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photographs. Katherine Anne Porter and Margaret Winkler[?]., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph. Katherine Anne Porter and unidentified person., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 1962, 1 item.
  - Invitation to reception for publication of Porter's Ship of Fools, April 2, 1962; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Journals, 4 items.
  - Accent, vol.6, no.4., (Spring 1946); 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    General note
    Both are inscribed Porter, p.[211].
  - Accent, vol.7, no.3., (Spring 1947).; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Inscribed by Porter, p.182.
  - Sewanee Review, vol.55, no.1., (Winter 1947).; 1 item. Inscribed by Porter, p.[1]. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Westwood Hills Press., 1947; 2 items.
  - Westwood Hills Press (vol.21, no.25, pp.1,6). "Katherine Anne Porter speaks on subject of writing novels.", July 10, 1947; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Westwood Hills Press (vol.21, no.41, pp.1, 6). "Katherine Anne Porter writes views on debate.", September 4, 1947; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 18)